Linux in open source operating system that makes it possible for humans to
play with computers it was created in 1991 by University of Helsinki student
1991 年赫尔辛基大学学生
Linus Torvalds his goal was to create a free version of the Minix operating
Linus Torvalds 创建的开源
system which itself was based on Unix today it's used everywhere like the vast
操作系统中的Linux 使人类可以玩计算机 无处不在，如
majority of web servers embedded apps like your smart TV mobile devices
绝大多数网络服务器嵌入式应用程序，如运行 Android 的智能电视移动设备
running Android and is by far the best choice for your personal computer with
，是迄今为止您的个人计算机的最佳选择，有
many different distros to choose from like Debian Arch and Fedora just to name
许多不同的发行版可供选择，如 Debian Arch 和 Fedora，
a few just like Windows or Mac OS Linux is an operating system that manages a
仅举几例，如 Windows 或 Mac OS Linux是一种操作系统，它管理
computer's memory and processes allowing Hardware to communicate with software
计算机的内存和进程，
when you fire up a Linux machine a bootloader will first put the system
当您启动 Linux 机器时，允许硬件与软件通信
into memory at its core we have the kernel which is like a seed from which
the rest of the operating system grows it's divided into multiple smaller
操作系统的其余部分不断增长，它分为多个较小的
subsystems like a process scheduler device drivers and a memory manager
子系统，例如进程调度程序设备驱动程序和备忘录 ry manager
they're exposed with a system call interface which itself is wrapped with
他们暴露了一个系统调用接口，该接口本身是
the c standard Library which provides an API that user applications can interact
用 c 标准库包装的，它提供了一个用户应用程序可以与之交互
with now beyond the kernel we have applications that make the OS usable for
的 API 现在超出内核我们有使操作系统可供人类使用的应用程序，
humans which are provided primarily via the gnu project like a shell to interact
这些应用程序主要通过 gnu 项目就像一个 shell
with the kernel from the command line windowing systems on desktop developer
从桌面开发实用程序上的命令行窗口系统
utilities and countless other applications to get started install your
和无数其他应用程序上与内核交互 开始安装您
favorite Linux distro open the terminal and notice how we're logged in as the
最喜欢的 Linux 发行版 打开终端并注意我们是如何以
root user on a specific Linux machine currently we're in the home directory of
root 用户身份登录的 Linux 机器目前我们在 root 用户的主目录中，
the root user which is shortened to this tilde character show its full name with
该目录被缩短为这个波浪字符显示它的全名
the print working directory command now use change directories with a double
使用打印工作目录命令现在使用带有双
period to go to the root of the file system use the ls command to print all
句点的更改目录以转到文件系统的根目录使用 ls 命令
the subdirectories here these are your critical system files let's go back home
在这里打印所有子目录 这些是您的关键系统文件 让我们
with CD tilde now create a new file with touch then edit it from the terminal
带着 CD 回家 现在创建一个新的 fi  le withtouch 然后
with a tool like VI Vim Nano or emacs in Vim type Ida insert write your
使用 VI Vim Nano 或Vim 类型中的 emacs 等工具从终端编辑它 Ida 插入 写你的
screenplay hit Escape then colon WQ to write it to the file system now use the
剧本 点击 Escape 然后冒号 WQ 将其写入文件系统 现在使用
cat command to read the file if it's really big use grep to find all the
cat 命令读取文件，如果它真的 big 使用 grep 查找
lines in that file that contain in a search term or pattern if we want to see
该文件中包含搜索词或模式的所有行如果我们想查看
how big that file is we can enter the disk usage command every file has an
该文件有多大，我们可以输入磁盘使用命令每个文件都有一个
owner and a set of permissions assigned to it we can change the owner with the
所有者和一组分配给它的权限 现在可以使用
Chone command or its permissions with chamod now if your current user doesn't
Chone 命令更改所有者或
have proper permissions you can put super user do in front of any command to
run it with elevated privileges to install new software on this machine we
使用 chamod 更改其权限
can use a package manager like Advanced package tool which will retrieve the
使用高级包工具之类的包管理器，它将
code from the cloud and place it in the proper location on your system we just
从云中检索代码并将其放置在您系统上的适当位置我们刚刚
went through a bunch of commands let's recap everything with history this has
经历了一堆命令让我们用历史回顾一下这
been Linux in 100 seconds if you want to see more short videos like this hit the
一直是 Linu  x 100 秒内如果你想看更多这样的短视频点击
like button and subscribe thanks for watching and I will see you in the next
喜欢按钮并订阅感谢观看，我会在下一个看到你
one